As our first function,
我们要编写的第一个函数是
we'll write a function that calculates the volume of a cylinder.
计算圆柱体体积的函数
The formula for this is the cylinder's height,
用到的公式是圆柱体的高
multiplied by the square of its radius, multiplied by pi.
乘以半径的平方 再乘以 π
Here's what that formula looks like when defined in a function called cylinder volume.
这是使用函数 cylinder_volume 定义该公式的代码
After defining the cylinder volume function,
定义 cylinder_volume 函数之后
we can use it like this.
我们可以像这样使用它
This value is the volume of a cylinder 10 inches tall with a radius of three inches.
这个值是高 10 英寸 半径 3 英寸的圆柱体的体积
Let's see how this works behind the scenes.
我们来看看背后的原理
A function definition includes several important parts.
函数定义包括几个重要的部分
First, let's look at the function header.
首先 我们来看看函数头部
Defining a function always starts with
定义函数时始终以关键字 def 开头
the def keyword to indicate that the code that follows is a function definition,
表示接下来的代码是一个函数定义
and ends with a colon.
并以冒号结束
Following def is the name of the function.
def 之后是函数的名称
In this case, cylinder_volume.
在此示例中 名称是 cylinder_volume
This needs to be a one word with no gaps.
名称必须是一个单词 不能有空格
That's why this has an underscore.
因此我们使用了下划线
The rules for function names are the same as those for variable names.
函数名称的规则和变量名称的一样
If you need a reminder on this,
如果你要复习这方面的知识
see the text below this video.
请参阅本视频下方的文字
After the function name are parentheses that
函数名称之后是小括号
includes the arguments that the function expects, separated by commas.
其中包含函数会接受的参数 用英文逗号分隔
These arguments are values that are passed in as inputs
这些参数是当函数被调用时 作为输入函数中的值
when the function is called and are used in this body.
并用在这个主体中
If you write a function that doesn't take arguments,
如果函数没有参数
then just leave these parentheses empty.
则直接使这些括号为空
Here is an example of a function that takes no arguments.
这是一个没有参数的函数
In this case, there is no input data we want to work with in the body of the function,
在这种情况下 我们在函数主体中不需要处理任何输入数据
so no arguments are necessary.
因此不需要任何参数
Next, let's discuss the body of a function.
接着 我们来讨论下函数主体
The body of the function is indented after
函数主体是在函数头部之后缩进的部分
the header and is where the function does its work.
函数在主体中执行操作
Within this body, we can refer to the argument variables and define new variables.
我们可以在此主体中引用参数变量并定义新的变量
The pi variable that we define here is a local variable.
我们在这里定义的变量 π 是一个局部变量
Meaning; it can only be used within the body of this function.
表示它只能在该函数的主体中使用
Attempting to access this variable outside the function isn't possible.
我们无法在该函数之外访问该变量
This is due to what is called variable scope,
这是由变量作用域造成的
which determines which variables you have access to in Python.
变量作用域会确定你可以在 Python 中访问哪些变量
We'll discuss this in detail later in the lesson.
我们将在这节课的稍后阶段详细讨论这一概念
Often, the body of a function will include
通常 函数主体将包括这个
this return key word which is used to
return 关键字
give back an output value when the function is called.
用于在调用函数时返回一个输出值
The value of the expression that follows return is the output of the function.
return 之后的表达式的值是函数的输出
In this example, we return the value evaluated from
在此示例中 我们返回用该公式计算的
this formula for the volume of a cylinder.
圆柱体体积值
Rather than returning the value as it is calculated,
我们可以先在函数主体中计算圆柱体的体积
an alternative technique would be to calculate the volume earlier in
然后将其存储在叫做 volume 变量中
the function body and then store it in a variable named volume.
而不是返回计算的值
In this case, we would return volume like this.
在这种情况下 我们可以像这样返回 volume
Functions like this can be imagined as little machines that take
这样的函数可以看做一个小机器
inputs or arguments and process them into output or return values.
该机器会接受输入或参数并处理成输出或返回值
This is a good image but it's incomplete.
这是一个很好的比喻 但是并不全面
Some functions like print don't return anything at all.
print() 等函数不返回任何内容
Print displays text on the output window but as we see here,
Print() 会在输出窗口上显示文本
the value it returns is none.
但是从该示例中可以看出返回的值是 None
None is when a function will return by
当函数没有明确返回任何其他内容时
default if it doesn't explicitly return anything else.
它将默认地返回 None
The difference between print and return is often confused.
print() 和 return 之间的区别经常让人困惑
Print provides output to the console while return provides
print() 向控制台提供输出
the value that you can store and work with and code later.
而 return 会提供你可以存储以便稍后在代码中使用的值
You'll get some practice with this in the quizzes that follow.
你将在下面的练习中进行这方面的实践
It's not necessary that every function has a return statement.
并非所有函数都有 return 语句
Notice this function, print_greeting,
注意 这个 print_greeting 函数
doesn't have a return statement,
没有 return 语句
but it's still a valid function.
但依然是有效的函数